# <a href="" target="_blank">Hunger Box</a> 
- A Java Web Developement Project
-  -Admin
- Bussines User
- Customer 

<hr>
<bold>About:</bold><br>
Users (presumably customers or beneficiaries) access the HungerBox platform or app.
They browse through food options available from hotels that have been approved and their menus uploaded by administrators.
Users can select meals they wish to purchase based on the available choices and their preferences.
Hotel Owners' Role:
Hotel owners or managers participate by uploading their food menus onto the HungerBox platform.
They ensure their menus are up-to-date and reflect the current offerings.

<hr>

<span style="color:blue">**Modules:-**</span><br>
<span style="color:red">**Admin**</span><br>
<span>&#9745;</span> Admin approved  the Hotels<br>
<span>&#9745;</span> View and maintaining registered hotel records<br>
<span>&#9745;</span> Admin delete unused user profile<br>
<span>&#9745;</span> Admin view the approved hotels menu details<br>
<br>
<span style="color:red">**BusinessUser**</span><br>
<span>&#9745;</span> Registered their hotels<br>
<span>&#9745;</span> Approved hotels upload the food menu<br>
<span>&#9745;</span> Edit and update their food menu and price detials<br>
<span>&#9745;</span> View user purchased foods in their hotel<br>
<br>
<span style="color:red">**Customer**</span><br>
<span>&#9745;</span> Register<br>
<span>&#9745;</span> View the food menu and click addtocart that foods are stored in view cart<br>
<span>&#9745;</span> Choosed foods are in  view cart and click paynow. Payment process<br>

<span style="color:blue">**Admin:-**</span><br>
<span>&#10004;</span> Admin Login.<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> Approved Registered Hotels<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> View registered Customer details<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> View approved hotel food menu<br>

<span style="color:blue">**BussinessUser:-**</span><br>
<span>&#10004;</span> Bussines Login.<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> Add food menu<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> View their hotel food menu <br>
<span>&#10004;</span> View their hotel user purchased foods<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> calculate their hotel purchaed foods overall amount<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> Approved user purchased foods delivery status on-process,delivery,ordered placed<br>


<span style="color:blue">**Customer:-**</span><br>
<span>&#10004;</span> Customer Login.<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> Food menu user side that is Addtocart.<br>
<span>&#10004;</span> User Purchaed foods are stored in viewcart<br>
<span>&#10004;</span>Payment Process <br>
<span>&#10004;</span> Delivery Status Track<br>


### Technologies used:-
1. Front-End Development:
- Html 5. 
- CSS.
- Javascript.

2. Back-End Development:
- Java [JDK 17]
- JDBC
- Spring Boot

3. Database:
- Oracle Sql

### ================ Software And Tools Required ================
- Eclipse
- Java [JDK 17]
- Tomcat v8.0+
- Apache Maven
- Editor Sql developer


### ================= Features  =================
<span style="color:blue">User Registration and Login:</span><br>
Users can easily register and log in to their accounts. This allows them to access personalized features, view their order history, and manage their profiles.

<span style="color:blue">Food Menu Management:</span><br>
Business users, such as hotel owners, can upload their menus for users to browse. The admin must approve all restaurant registrations to ensure quality and reliability.

<span style="color:blue">Cart Functionality:</span><br>
Users can add food items to their cart. The cart allows users to review their selections before proceeding to checkout, ensuring a smooth ordering experience.

<span style="color:blue">Secure Payment Processing:</span><br>
The system provides a secure payment gateway for users to complete their transactions. This feature ensures that all payment information is handled safely.

<span style="color:blue">Order Tracking:</span><br>
Users can track the status of their orders in real-time. Status updates include “Order Accepted,” “In Process,” and “Out for Delivery,” providing transparency throughout the delivery process.

<span style="color:blue">Admin Dashboard:</span><br>
Admins have access to a comprehensive dashboard for managing user accounts, overseeing restaurant registrations, and monitoring overall platform activity.

<span style="color:blue">User Notifications:</span><br>
Users receive notifications about their order status, promotional offers, and updates regarding their registered accounts to enhance engagement and user experience.


<br><a href=""> HungerBox User Manual</a><br>
<a href=""> HungerBox PPT</a>


